Ramon Garza III

(832) 773-7728 | ramong5406@gmail.com | Katy, TX 77493 linkedin.com/in/ramon-garza-908611199/ | github.com/Ramong06 | ramong.netlify.app/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front-End React Developer/Full Stack Developer leveraging nine years in oil and gas. Has a strong passion for innovation and a keen eye for aesthetics and presentation as well as knowledge of Continuous integration/deployment. Recently obtained a certificate in web development from the University of Texas, gaining experience while also honing my skills in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React and SQL. Excellent communication skills and collaborator who works well on team-based projects as well as independently. Recognized for problem-solving and ability to adapt and implement new information as a part of a fast-paced environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js., Express, JavaScript (ES 6+), jQuery, React.js, React 16.8+/Redux, JSX, GIT, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Mongoose, Handlebars, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Materialize, APIs, Heroku, Terminal, AJAX, Restful API, React Hooks, JSON, Sequelize, Java, Springboot, debugging, Excel, Vue.js, Python.

PROJECTS

Inside-Job | Full-Stack Developer | Deployed link: inside-job.herokuapp.com/ | Github page: github.com/Ramong06/inside-job :

A 3-page web application whose main goal is to serve as a research hub for individuals in the job market.

- **Role**: Collaborator. Used Reactjs to style components of the application's front-end while also using Excel, MongoDB, Studio3t to add company info data to be rendered to the search results page.
- **Utilized**: HTML, CSS, JSON, React, AJAX, MongoDB, Studio3t and APIs

Ask Winston | Full-Stack Developer | Deployed link: github.com/Ramong06/inside-job | Github page: github.com/On-Your-Marc-GO/Ask-Winston-Music-Rec-Engine

A web application that serves as a music recommendation search engine.

- **Role:** Collaborator. Used HTML, CSS, Javascript to style About, Contact and Home pages. Used AJAX calls to third-party APIs.
- Utilized: Materialize, Javascript, Jquery, Git, HTML 5 and CSS 3

A company directory application that allows you to search for a specific employee by email or name.

- **Role**: Sole Developer.
- Tools Utilized: HTML, CSS, ES 6, React, Bootstrap, Axios, Service Worker, and APIs

Continued...

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Spatial Consulting; Houston, TX 01/2018 - Present

Full Stack Developer

Interfacing and translating client's business requirements into technical applications and solutions. Tasked to handle end-to-end software development in a timely manner to meet contract deadlines while also assisting more experienced developers re-factor and debug their code.

- Increased efficiency and collaboration at work-place by assisting senior devs with front-end code.
- Debug and re-factor Java code using Eclipse IDE.
- Add property management and inventory information (photos, prices, descriptions etc.) into MySQL databases
- Use MongoDB and Studio3T to add construction company photos and projects.
- Utilize Chart.js to provide yearly and quarterly revenue information.
- Use Google Firebase to create User Authentication forms for private construction company.
- Utilize Visual Studio, Bootstrap 4, HTML, CSS, Jquery, Reactjs, Node.js to create dynamic and easy to navigate User Interfaces for private consulting companies. (All front-end applications were created in Visual Studio)
- Collaborate with team members to create mobile friendly UI.
- Constant learning through online resources to implement the latest software trends and libraries (i.e React.js, Angular.js, Vue.js

WOOD; TX 10/2011 - 12/2017

Multi-Skilled Operator (MSO)

Keep track of all single-well and multi-well facilities oil and natural gas production. Apply proper maintenance to equipment when and if necessary.

- Promoted after only one year to team Lead.
- Assigned the largest production facilities owned by the company.
- Awarded safety leader in 2012

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate - University of Texas; Houston, TX | 2020

A 24-week intensive boot camp program focused on gaining technical programming and market-driven skills.